class QuestionModel{
  final String question;
  final List<String> options;
  final correctAnswerIndex;
  final String Solution;

  const QuestionModel({
    required this.question,
    required this.options,
    required this.correctAnswerIndex,
    required this.Solution,
  });
}
List<QuestionModel> orderind_and_ranking = [



QuestionModel(
question: "1. What is the rank of India in terms of population among the countries of the world?",
options: [
"A. 2nd",
"B. 5th",
"C. 7th",
"D. 10th"
],
correctAnswerIndex: 2,
Solution: "India is ranked 2nd in the world in terms of population, with over 1.3 billion people."
),

QuestionModel(
question: "2. Which Indian state has the highest population?",
options: [
"A. Maharashtra",
"B. Uttar Pradesh",
"C. Bihar",
"D. West Bengal"
],
correctAnswerIndex: 1,
Solution: "Uttar Pradesh has the highest population among Indian states, making it the most populous state in India."
),

QuestionModel(
question: "3. What is the population of India as of the 2021 Census?",
options: [
"A. 1 billion",
"B. 1.3 billion",
"C. 1.5 billion",
"D. 2 billion"
],
correctAnswerIndex: 1,
Solution: "As of the 2021 Census, India's population is approximately 1.3 billion."
),

QuestionModel(
question: "4. Which city is the capital of India?",
options: [
"A. Mumbai",
"B. Delhi",
"C. Kolkata",
"D. Chennai"
],
correctAnswerIndex: 1,
Solution: "Delhi is the capital city of India."
),

QuestionModel(
question: "5. In which year did India gain independence from British colonial rule?",
options: [
"A. 1942",
"B. 1947",
"C. 1950",
"D. 1962"
],
correctAnswerIndex: 1,
Solution: "India gained independence from British colonial rule on August 15, 1947."
),

QuestionModel(
question: "6. Who was the first Prime Minister of India?",
options: [
"A. Jawaharlal Nehru",
"B. Sardar Vallabhbhai Patel",
"C. Indira Gandhi",
"D. Rajendra Prasad"
],
correctAnswerIndex: 0,
Solution: "Jawaharlal Nehru served as the first Prime Minister of India."
),

QuestionModel(
question: "7. What is the official currency of India?",
options: [
"A. Rupee",
"B. Taka",
"C. Yen",
"D. Dollar"
],
correctAnswerIndex: 0,
Solution: "The official currency of India is the Indian Rupee (INR)."
),

QuestionModel(
question: "8. Which mountain range forms the northern border of India?",
options: [
"A. Himalayas",
"B. Western Ghats",
"C. Eastern Ghats",
"D. Vindhya Range"
],
correctAnswerIndex: 0,
Solution: "The Himalayas form the northern border of India."
),

QuestionModel(
question: "9. What is the largest state in India by area?",
options: [
"A. Maharashtra",
"B. Rajasthan",
"C. Madhya Pradesh",
"D. Uttar Pradesh"
],
correctAnswerIndex: 1,
Solution: "Rajasthan is the largest state in India by land area."
),

QuestionModel(
question: "10. Which river is often referred to as the 'Ganga' in India?",
options: [
"A. Brahmaputra",
"B. Yamuna",
"C. Godavari",
"D. Indus"
],
correctAnswerIndex: 1,
Solution: "The Yamuna river is often referred to as the 'Ganga' in India."
),
QuestionModel(
question: "11. Which Indian state has the highest literacy rate?",
options: [
"A. Kerala",
"B. Bihar",
"C. Uttar Pradesh",
"D. Madhya Pradesh"
],
correctAnswerIndex: 0,
Solution: "Kerala has the highest literacy rate among Indian states, making it one of the most educated states in India."
),

QuestionModel(
question: "12. What is the highest civilian award in India?",
options: [
"A. Padma Shri",
"B. Bharat Ratna",
"C. Padma Bhushan",
"D. Param Vir Chakra"
],
correctAnswerIndex: 1,
Solution: "The Bharat Ratna is the highest civilian award in India, given for exceptional service in various fields."
),

QuestionModel(
question: "13. Who is known as the 'Father of the Indian Constitution'?",
options: [
"A. Mahatma Gandhi",
"B. Sardar Patel",
"C. Dr. B.R. Ambedkar",
"D. Jawaharlal Nehru"
],
correctAnswerIndex: 2,
Solution: "Dr. B.R. Ambedkar is known as the 'Father of the Indian Constitution' for his significant role in its drafting."
),

QuestionModel(
question: "14. What is the national flower of India?",
options: [
"A. Rose",
"B. Lotus",
"C. Sunflower",
"D. Marigold"
],
correctAnswerIndex: 1,
Solution: "The Lotus is the national flower of India, symbolizing purity and spirituality."
),

QuestionModel(
question: "15. Which Indian city is often called the 'City of Joy'?",
options: [
"A. Kolkata",
"B. Mumbai",
"C. Delhi",
"D. Chennai"
],
correctAnswerIndex: 0,
Solution: "Kolkata is often referred to as the 'City of Joy' due to its cultural richness and vibrant life."
),

QuestionModel(
question: "16. Which Indian state is known as the 'Land of Five Rivers'?",
options: [
"A. Haryana",
"B. Punjab",
"C. Rajasthan",
"D. Gujarat"
],
correctAnswerIndex: 1,
Solution: "Punjab is known as the 'Land of Five Rivers' due to its geographical location."
),

QuestionModel(
question: "17. What is the longest river in India?",
options: [
"A. Yamuna",
"B. Ganges",
"C. Brahmaputra",
"D. Godavari"
],
correctAnswerIndex: 2,
Solution: "The Brahmaputra River is the longest river in India, flowing through several states."
),

QuestionModel(
question: "18. Which Indian state is famous for the production of Darjeeling tea?",
options: [
"A. Assam",
"B. West Bengal",
"C. Kerala",
"D. Karnataka"
],
correctAnswerIndex: 1,
Solution: "West Bengal, specifically the Darjeeling region, is famous for the production of Darjeeling tea."
),

QuestionModel(
question: "19. What is the largest national park in India by area?",
options: [
"A. Jim Corbett National Park",
"B. Kaziranga National Park",
"C. Sundarbans National Park",
"D. Hemis National Park"
],
correctAnswerIndex: 3,
Solution: "Hemis National Park in Ladakh, Jammu and Kashmir, is the largest national park in India by area."
),

QuestionModel(
question: "20. Which Indian state is known for its sand dunes and desert landscape?",
options: [
"A. Rajasthan",
"B. Goa",
"C. Himachal Pradesh",
"D. Tamil Nadu"
],
correctAnswerIndex: 0,
Solution: "Rajasthan is known for its sand dunes and desert landscape, particularly in the Thar Desert."
),






];